你昨晚很晚才回来  有案子吗
You got in late last night. Catch a case?
是的
Yeah.
就是报上的这桩案子
Actually, it was this one.
有人炸了市中心一间公寓
Someone blew up an apartment downtown.
不是吧  你居然没打电话给我
Seriously? And you didn't call me?
卡塞尔  你说你有一章必须要写完
Castle, you said you had a chapter due.
对于作家来说  潜台词就是"尽请耽误我吧"
Yes, which is writer speak for "All procrastination's welcome".
是什么情况  恐怖分子阴谋  毒品工厂
So what was it, a terrorist plot, a meth lab?
排查到有一名男子
The canvass turned up a description of a guy
驾驶银色掀背式汽车逃离现场
fleeing the scene in a silver hatchback.
我们申请了交通监控录像
And we called in for traffic cam footage...
有可能有结果了  我得走了
Which is probably already in, so I gotta get going.
或者  你可以叫埃斯波西托查看录像
Or... You could have Esposito check that out.
他很擅长这个  我感觉好久没看到你了
He's very good at it. I feel like I haven't seen you in days.
我真的得走了  但是
You know, I really do have to get going,but--
但是你无力拒绝我  你一直是这样
But you're powerless to resist me. You always have been.
真的吗
Really?
还记得我们初次见面吗  我觉得你是个混蛋
Do you remember when we first met? I kinda thought you were an ass.
我知道你假装成那样  但是别装了
Oh, I know you pretended you thought that. But come on.
我们现在在一起了  你可以承认了
We're together now. You can admit it.
你对我  是一见钟情
You fell for me the first moment you saw me.
-我没有  -拜托  你就是
- No, I didn't. - Please. You did.
-你真这样想  对吗  -这是事实
- You believe that, don't you? - It's true.
等等
Oh, hold on.
好  我马上来
Okay. I'll be right there.
交通监控录像中已经找到了匹配车牌
Traffic cam footage turned up a match to the plates.
-找到人了  -非常好
- We got him. - Nice.
等等  等等
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
-看到杯里的心了吗  -我们走  卡塞尔
- Did you see the hearts? - Let's go, Castle.
花了我  大约六分钟时间
Took me, like... six minutes.
车牌登记在阿奇博尔德·弗希名下
The car's license plate was registered to Archibald Fosse.
他独自一人住在一栋四层的公寓
He lives alone in a fourth-floor apartment.
这也不是他第一次犯案
This isn't his first rodeo, either.
他六年前赌马失败
He got in trouble playing the ponies
用汽车炸弹解决掉了他的投注人
so he took out his bookie with a car bomb six years ago.
才六年他就被放出来了吗
Six years and he's already out?
他本来是应该被判20年到无期的
Well, he was supposed to do 20 years to life.
但他的案子三个月前上诉成功
But his case got overturned on appeal three months ago.
知道昨晚爆炸的动机吗
Any idea about the motivation for last night's bombing?
不知道  20分钟前刚确定他的身份
No, we just ID'ed him 20 minutes ago.
还有许多情况我们不知道
There's a lot we have to learn about him yet.
贝克特  这位是迪亚哥·胡梅纳兹
Yo, Beckett. This is Diego Jiminez.
他去见弗希先生  被警员拦了下来
Uniforms intercepted him on his way up to pay Mr. Fosse a visit.
你怎么认识他的
How do you know him?
我不认识  真的  我根本没见过他
I don't, really. I've never even met him.
我们是网上联系的  我是个收藏家
We connected on-line. I'm a collector.
他说他有些三十年代的棒球卡想卖
He said he had some baseball cards from the '30s he wanted to sell.
就是这样
That's all.
至少我们知道
Well, we know this much.
如果迪亚哥约好和他见面  弗希可能在家
If Diego had an appointment, Fosse's probably in there.
警察  快快  上上上
Police! Move! Move! Go! Go! Go!
纽约警察
NYPD!
莱恩  埃斯波  他朝你们过去了
Ryan, Espo, he's coming your way.
不许动  纽约警察
Freeze! NYPD!
举起双手
Let me see your hands.
扔下  马上扔下
Drop it! Drop it now!
这是什么  为什么在闪光
What is that? Why is it flashing?
回答我  回答我
Answer me! Answer me!
棒球卡  和他说的一样
Baseball cards, just like he said.
贝克特  卡塞尔  马上离开
Beckett, Castle, get outta there now.
嫌疑人的口袋里有一种什么装置
The suspect had some kind of device in his pocket.
我想他装了炸弹
I think he armed something.
收到  所有人出去  快走  大家快走
Copy that. Everyone out now. Let's go. You guys, out.
怎么回事
What was that?
卡塞尔
Castle...
我想我站在炸弹上
I think I'm standing on a bomb.
你觉得我们要在这里站多久
How long do you think we'll have to stand here?
一旦拆弹小组结束检查
Once bomb disposal finishes their sweep,
就会知道是否有其它炸弹
we'll know if there are any other bombs you could step on,
还是说我站在唯一的炸弹上
or if I'm standing on the only one.
还不知道那是不是炸弹呢  也许没什么
We don't know that you're standing on a bomb. It could be nothing.
感觉不像没什么  我脚下有东西陷下去了
It didn't feel like nothing. Something gave way under my feet.
感觉像是触发器
It felt like a trigger plate.
有可能是松动的地板
Could be a wonky floorboard.
会有金属的滴答声吗
With a metallic click?
钉子松了  所以木地板才会松动
Loose nail. That's how floorboards get wonky.
希望你是对的
Well, I hope you're right.
我是对的  想想吧
I'm right. I mean, think about it.
谁会把炸弹放在自己的家里
Who puts a live bomb in their own apartment?
没有道理
It makes no sense.
你饿了吗
You hungry?
为什么问
Why?
因为随时会有人从那道门进来
Because any minute, someone's gonna come through that door
告诉我们安全了
and give us the all clear.
离这里不到三条街  有家非常棒的小吃店
And there is an amazing diner not three blocks from here.
我今早的确没吃早餐
Yeah? Well,I did miss my breakfast this morning.
是的
Yeah.
他们家的拿铁泡沫丰富  可好喝了
They make these incredible, foamy lattes--
杯子有你脑袋那么大
Cups as big as your head--
山羊奶酪煎蛋卷真是好吃到死
And a goat cheese omelet to die for.
我可能用词不当
Which would be a poor choice of words
如果你真的站在炸弹上的话  不过你猜怎样
if you were standing on a bomb, but guess what.
你没有站在炸弹上
You're not.
如果我非得被困住
You know, if I have to be, uh, stuck...
不是站在炸弹上  我很高兴是和你困在一起
Not standing on a bomb, then I'm glad I'm stuck with you.
我知道
I know.
我是拆弹小组的马霍尼警监
Captain Mahoney, bomb disposal unit.
你们谁是贝克特探长
Which one of you is detective Beckett?
我是贝克特探长  这位是卡塞尔
I'm detective Beckett. This is Castle.
卡塞尔  你可以放轻松
Castle, you can relax.
我们在楼下用X光检查了整间公寓
We've x-rayed the entire apartment from the floor below.
没有其它爆炸物
There are no other explosives.
没有其它爆炸物  那么
No other explosives? So...
探长  恐怕你站在
Detective, I'm afraid you've stepped on
连接炸药的传感器上
a sensor plate wired to a detonator.
传感器上负重  就像是扣上了枪的扳机
Depressing that plate was sort of like cocking the hammer of a gun.
你离开  重量消失  就等同开枪
You take your weight off there, it's like pulling the trigger.
所以最重要的就是你不能动
So it's very important that you don't move
直到我们想到办法拆弹为止
until we figure out how to disarm it.
拆弹小组刚刚确认了
B.D.U. just confirmed it.
贝克特站在炸弹上
Beckett's standing on a bomb.
痕量探测估算有十公斤炸药
Trace detection estimates 10 kilograms of R.D.X.
足以炸毁整栋公寓
Enough to take out the whole building.
有什么打算
So what's the plan?
长官  他们有所打算的吧
Sir, tell me there's a plan.
他们在处理  那个炸弹狂查得怎么样
They're working on it. What do we have on that bomber?
看样子作案动机是为了报仇
Looks like his motive was revenge.
凯利·兰瑟  那个昨晚被他炸死的女人
Kelly Runther, the woman he blew up last night,
六年前曾指证他纵火
testified against him at his arson trial six years ago.
那为什么要在自家公寓放炸弹
Then why would he booby-trap his own apartment?
审讯时辩方声称
The defense at his trial centered on allegations
警方篡改了证物
of evidence tampering by police, so...
所以他憎恨警察
He's got a vendetta against cops.
是的  长官  他一手策划了此事
Yes, sir. He wanted this to happen.
别让他得逞
Well, we're not gonna let it.
问出点东西来
You get him in the box.
我要知道怎么拆除那个炸弹
I want to know how to deactivate that bomb.
你们凭什么觉得那炸弹可以拆除
What makes you think it can be deactivated?
你最好祈祷可以  因为站在那炸弹上的人
You better pray that it can, because the person standing on it,
是我的朋友
she's a friend of mine.
那她命不久矣了
Not for long.
你错了
That's where you're wrong.
你会帮我们  你知道那炸弹是怎么制造的
See, you're gonna help us. You know how the bomb is made.
雷管  起爆装置  还有其它小部件
The detonator, the fuse, all the other little parts--
要是他们能让任何一部分失灵  炸弹就不会爆
If they can stop any one of those parts from working, the bomb fails.
炸弹一定会爆炸  这还没完呢
It's not gonna fail. I'm not done yet.
这事还远远没完
None of this is over.
那你就会以警察杀手的身份重回监狱
Well, then you're going back to jail a cop killer,
还没有哪座监狱...
and there's not a prison around that's gonna--
你们想救朋友吗  给我找个律师
You want to save your friend? I want a lawyer.
马上去
Now.
我们估计触发板大约在三乘三英尺范围内
We're estimating the trigger plate is about 3 feet by 3 feet.
别跨过这条线
So no one crosses this line.
拆除过程一般要多久
And the disarming process, how long does that usually take?
要看炸弹了
Well, that depends on the bomb.
我们还不清楚这是个怎样的炸弹
We still don't know what kind of device we're dealing with.
那我们现在要干什么
So what are we supposed to do in the meantime,
你不能让她就这么站着
just--you can't have her just stand there.
我没事的  卡塞尔
I'm okay, Castle.
不  你有事  你正站在...
No, you're not okay. You're standing...
你说过  站在触发板上就相当于拉起枪栓
Look, you said, uh, stepping on the plate was like cocking the hammer.
从触发板上下来相当于扣下扳机
stepping off the plate was pulling the trigger.
要是用和贝克特相同重量的东西换下她呢
What if we replaced Beckett with something of equal weight?
就好像《夺宝奇兵》里一袋沙换一袋金的把戏
You know, just the old Indiana Jones bag of sand/golden idol trick.
记得结局怎样吗
Remember how that turned out?
她所站的触发板
Look, the plate she's standing on can sense
能探测到轻微的压力波动
even minor fluctuations in pressure.
要想偷梁换柱  就会引爆炸弹
You try to transfer the weight, you'll set off the bomb.
在她身上加任何防护装备  也会引爆炸弹
Put any kind of protective gear on her, you'll set off the bomb.
她快速换一条腿...
She shifts too quickly from one foot to the other--
还会引爆炸弹  我明白了
Set off the bomb. I-I get it.
谢谢  很抱歉我这么问你
Thank you. I'm sorry I asked.
那我们该做什么  傻站着吗
So what are we supposed to do, just stand here?
你不必站在这里  卡塞尔先生
Not you, Mr. Castle.
无关人士必须撤离
All nonessential personnel must evacuate.
不  我关系可大了
Oh, no. I am essential personnel.
卡塞尔  没事的
Castle, it's okay.
我们会好好照顾她的
We'll take good care of her.
我的人就在楼下想对策
I got guys downstairs right now figuring this out.
与此同时  探长  不要轻举妄动
Meantime, detective, sit tight.
我很快就回来看你
I'll check back with you soon.
谢了  我要待在这里
I appreciate it. I'm staying.
卡塞尔  拜托  没道理让你犯险
Castle, please. There is no reason to put yourself in danger.
你也束手无策
There's nothing that you can do here.
束手无策  请问谁来做你的炸友
Nothing? Excuse me. Who's gonna be your bomb buddy?
炸友
My bomb buddy?
你也听到他说的话了
You heard what he said.
你可能要在这儿站上好几个小时
You're gonna be standing here, maybe for hours.
我不在的话  谁来鼓励你
If I don't stay, who's gonna keep your spirits up?
谁来给你加油打气
Who's gonna take your mind off of getting tired?
卡塞尔  我没事的  我现在很好
Castle, I'm gonna be fine. I feel fine.
如果你清楚自己的感受  那听你这么说真是好事
That would be great if you were a reliable judge of your own feelings,
但显然  你不清楚
which clearly, you're not.
什么意思
What does that mean?
不好意思  首先  据你自己所说
I'm sorry. Exhibit "A"-- according to you,
我们初遇时你对我毫无感觉
you felt nothing for me when we first met,
-而我们都知道...  -你这是...我明白了
- which we both know... - Are you act--oh,I get it.
-我明白你这是干什么了  -干什么
- I know what you're doing. - What?
你知道吗  卡塞尔  算了吧
You know what, Castle? Forget it.
我不会上套的  你快走吧
I'm not going down that path. You can just go now.
好吧  你承认我们初遇时
Fine, I'll leave if you admit to me
你就对我有感觉  那我就走
you had feelings for me when we first met.
好吧  我们初遇时我就对你有感觉
Fine. I did have feelings for you when we first met.
特受不了你的感觉
I couldn't stand you.
你还记得一开始你什么样吗
Do you even remember what you were like in the beginning?
很明显  我魅力无边
Well, apparently, I was irresistible.
魅力无边  开什么玩笑
Irresistible? Are you joking?
理查德·卡塞尔  我们以妨碍司法公正将你逮捕
Richard Castle, you are under arrest for obstruction of justice.
你忘记加上让你丢脸这条了
You forgot making you look bad.
铐上他
Cuff him.
捆绑啊  我的安全词是"苹果"
Bondage. My safe word is "apples".
猜猜谁刚约了妓女
Guess who's got a date with a prostitute?
好多寂寞的女人靠近我
So many lonely women approached me
想着我是她们的汤姆·汉克斯
thinking I was their Tom Hanks.
-我就...  -卡塞尔
- I got la- - Castle.
不要逼我开枪打你
Don't make me shoot you.
我真是全身散发着粗旷美啊  是不
I really am ruggedly handsome, aren't I?
我要杀了你
I am gonna kill you.
我是现在就杀了他  还是等他签完协议呢
Do I have to wait for him to sign, or can I shoot him now?
-你到底有多肤浅  -非常  肤浅
- How shallow are you? - Very.
再叫我女神  我就打断你的腿
Call me a muse again, and I will break both your legs.
-懂吗  -懂了
- Okay? - Okay.
做梦去吧
In your dreams.
其实  在我的梦里你从来不吃醋
Actually, in my dreams, you're never jealous.
在我的梦里  你会一起来...
In my dreams,you just join in--ooh.
好吧  要是我们初遇时你受不了我  那告诉我
Okay. If you couldn't stand me when we first met,tell me this.
你怎么就对我欲罢不能呢
Why couldn't you keep your hands off me?
你到底在说什么
What are you even talking about?
你心里明白
Oh, you know what I'm talking about.
好的  我马上过去
Okay. Of course. Sure. I'll be right there.
松手  松手
Apples. Apples. Apples.
牵住我的手
Hold my hand.
卡塞尔  那是为了生存
That? Castle, that was called survival.
我们是在抱团取暖
We were just huddling for warmth.
-拥抱  -抱团
- Cuddling? - Huddling.
或者以点及面来看
Or one could see it as a small part of a larger pattern--
这是工作场所不必要的肢体接触
unwanted touching in the workplace.
你被我骚扰了  是这意思吗
Oh, so you're being harassed? Is that it?
你很幸运
You know, you're very lucky.
要不是我通情达理  肯定要为你对我说的那些
A less understanding man would press charges with all the...
不合适的话告你的
inappropriate things you've said to me.
是嘛  什么话
Really? Like what?
神呐  这姿势到底怎么摆出来的
Oh, jeez. How do you even get in that position?
我就说吧  根本没可能
Right? It's not even possible.
还是有可能的
Oh, it's possible.
用你左手掌托住右手
Okay, gauntlet your right fist in your left palm.
枪开早了
Shot too soon.
我们抱抱就可以了  卡塞尔
You know, we could always just cuddle, Castle.
你刚用了"名副其实"这个词吗
Did you just use the word "Veritable"?
-是的  -很性感嘛
- Yes, I did. - Sexy.
你该听听我说"荒谬至极"
You should hear me say "Fallacious.
我与艺术课程最近的距离
The closest I ever came to taking an art class
只是在一堂课上做过模特
was posing for one as a model.
等等  是什么造型
Wait. Posing in?
赤裸酮体
Not a stitch.
怎么了  卡塞尔  害怕角色扮演吗
What's the matter, Castle? You afraid of a little role play?
就这些吗
That's it? That's all you got?
还有呢  但是回想起来
There's more, but on thinking back,
我瞬间有点被你
I was momentarily distracted
这些年的各种发型分神了
by your dizzying array of hairstyles over the years.
总之
Anyway...
卡塞尔  让我穿着泳装在烈日下暴晒吗
Oh, Castle, me in a swimsuit under the hot... Blistering sun?
我很乐意给你擦防晒霜
I'd be happy to rub lotion on you.
这就让你兴奋了吗
You think this is crazy,
你该见识一下我曾经去过的俱乐部
you should see some of the clubs I've been to.
有什么拿手的把戏
You know any good tricks?
我有一个拿手把戏就是大变冰块
I do this one thing with ice cubes.
但的确有件激情的  狂野的
There is one hot... Wild...
出格的事情我喜欢做
kinky thing that I do like doing.
就是将凶手绳之以法
Putting killers behind bars.
别闹了  直接放进去看看吧
Please, let's just stick it in and get this over with.
我根本不是那个意思
That's not how I meant it.
如果你喜欢乱解释我的话我也没办法
I can't help it if you get off by putting things in my mouth.
瞧见没  就这样  我都没...这太不可思议了
See? Like that. I can't even-- it's uncanny.
就好像你没说过不合适的话
Oh, like you've never been inappropriate.
我
Me?
我一直都很有绅士风度
I've never been anything but a perfect gentleman.
是吗
Really?
你放纵过自己吗  放松一下  脱掉上衣
You ever have any fun? Let your hair down? Drop your top?
做一个"狂野的警察"
A little "Cops gone wild"?
你知道我带枪了吧
You do know I'm wearing a gun?
有胆量的话  拜托让我输个精光
Yes, please. Beat my pants off if you dare.
-性行为  -我待会儿再给你解释
- Sex? - i'll explain how that works later.
思春的小护士
Slutty nurse.
你很会指使男人嘛
You're very good at bossing men around.、
这太火辣了
I find that hot.
让我告诉你什么叫疯子
Let me tell you something about crazy people.
今早爽得简直是不可思议
The sex is unbelievable.
打电话来是要给我讲睡前故事吗
Did you call to tell me a bedtime story?
我很高兴能让你打我一顿
I'd be happy to let you spank me.
我们被铐住了
We're handcuffed.
重口啊
Kinky.
不可思议地振奋人心
Strangely arousing.
你最好别乐在其中  卡塞尔
You better not be enjoying this, Castle.
我等会儿再向你汇报
I'll let you know in a minute.
如果你不喜欢穿泳装的话  你可以裸泳哦
If you are not comfortable in a swimsuit, you can just skinny-dip.
我穿短裤  那你穿什么呢
So I wear boxers. What do you wear?
丁字裤  性感小裤裤  灯笼裤
Thong? Cheekies? Bloomers?
保守型内裤  难道你不穿内裤
Granny panties? Commando?
还好意思说不必要的肢体接触呢
And talk about unwanted touching?
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready? - Yep.
好吧  我要上去了  准备好了吗
Okay. I'm gonna go up. Ready?
抓住我的腿
Grab my legs.
卡塞尔  我说的是腿好吗
Castle, I said "Legs, " Okay?
是腿啊  抱歉
Oh, legs. Sorry.
但那只是因为你的腿跟你的那个
Yeah, but that's simply because your legs are so close to your...
很近嘛
other bits.
是啊  继续骗你自己吧  卡塞尔
Oh, yeah. Keep telling yourself that, Castle.
-不会有事吧  -当然了
- It's gonna be okay right? - Yeah.
楼下那些人  他们都做过几千次了
Those guys downstairs, They've done this thousands of times.
马霍尼警监  战术小队询问最新情况
Captain Mahoney. Tactical wants an update.
接触不到炸弹  我们没什么办法了
Well, lack of access is limiting our options.
你们在他手持遥控器上查到了什么
What'd you find out about that handheld remote he had?
绝对是它启动了炸弹
It definitely activated the bomb.
好消息是  技术人员认为遥控器可以接触炸弹
Good news? Tech thinks it could deactivate it as well.
但我们需要正确的五位密码
But we need the right 5-digit code.
那得有十万种可能性吗
That's, what, a hundred thousand combinations?
而且它是防干扰的
Yeah, and it's tamper proof.
如果输错密码
Enter the wrong code, and...
我的客户说他愿意交出拆除密码  但是
My client says that he's willing to give you the disarm code, but...
他有些要求
He has some demands.
完全豁免  开玩笑呢
Full amnesty? You gotta be kidding me, right?
他昨晚就杀了一个人
This guy killed someone last night.
无法证实
Uh, allegedly killed.
听我说  我跟他说你们不会同意的
Look, I know. I-I told him that you wouldn't go for it,
但如果你还没发现  他精神不太正常
but if you haven't noticed, he's got a screw loose.
其他这些我都能满足
I can work on these other things--
食物  衣物  甚至电话也有可能
Food, clothes, even the phone isn't impossible, but--
他说他不愿回监狱
He said he won't go back to prison. Okay?
让他走  否则他就不帮她
He walks or he won't help her.
-你叫博耶  是吗  -对
- Boyer, right? - Yeah.
你法学院毕业多久了  两三年吗
You been out of law school, what, two, three years?
-十个月  -十个月
- Ten months. - Ten months?
-对  -好  听我说
- Yeah. - Okay, listen to me.
那个站在炸弹上的探长  她不能有事
That detective standing on that bomb, she needs to get through this.
懂吗
You understand me?
我发誓  我已经尽力了
Look, I-I swear. I'm--I'm doing what I can.
好吧  我拿这份清单去找地检官
All right. I'll take this list to the D. A.,
但我们得想个备用计划
but we're gonna need a plan "B.
地检官不同意  这不能怪他
The D. A. 's not going for it, nor should he.
为了救一个人而把这个疯子放回社会上
Turning this madman loose on society to save a single life,
哪怕是为了救她  也有违我们一切的宗旨
even hers, is against everything we stand for.
贝克特肯定也会这么想的
Beckett--she'd be the first to agree with that.
我再去找那个律师
I'll go back to the lawyer.
看他能不能说动弗希
See if he can get through to Fosse.
我告诉他交易是可以的  但是豁免不行
So I told him that there was a deal to be had, just not for amnesty--
-然后呢  -他还是坚持要豁免
- And? - And he's still insisting he walk.
我想给他几分钟想想  再去劝他
I figured I'd give him a few minutes to think and try again.
警探  我发誓  我真的尽力了
Detective, I swear, I'm doing everything I can.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thanks. - Yeah.
帮我个忙
Yo, do me a favor?
你能帮我拖住那个小律师一会儿吗
Why don't you keep junior over there busy for me, will you?
我去探视一下拘留室里那小子
I'm gonna go see our boy in holding.
干什么
Why?
你不是想要密码吗
You want that code, right?
-哈维尔  你要干什么  -那得看他的了
- Javi, what are you gonna do? - That's up to him.
医务人员  叫一名医务人员来拘留室
Medic! I need a medic in holding now!
他怎么拿到钢笔的
How in the hell did he get that pen?
那个律师给他的
That friggin' lawyer gave it to him.
他想劝服弗希提出别的要求
He was trying to encourage Fosse to come up with some alternate demands.
可他却害我们失去了拿到拆掉密码的机会
And instead he just cost us any hope Of getting that disarm code.
这家伙几个月前才出狱
The guy just got out of prison a couple of months ago.
他为什么要杀人  又为什么自杀
Why would he start killing people, and why would he take his own life?
我想我知道
I think I can answer that.
我查到弗希是脑癌晚期
Turns out... Fosse had stage iv brain cancer.
他上个月得知的  死亡只是早晚的事了
Found out last month. He was gonna die anyway.
既然要死  那不如拉上敌人一起死
So if he was dying, why not take his enemies with him?
没错  而且他的仇人不只有警察
Exactly, and his enemies weren't limited to cops
和昨晚死于炸弹的被害人
and last night's bombing victim.
上周康涅狄格州也发生了一起爆炸
There was another bombing last week in Connecticut.
死者曾为六年前把弗希
That victim worked for the A. D. A.
关进大牢的副地检工作
that put Fosse in jail six years ago.
弗希说过  "这还没完呢"
Hey, Fosse said, "I'm not done yet.
列出一份他那件案子所有跟控方有关的人
Make a list of everyone involved with the prosecution at his trial.
我们得警告他们  可能还有别的炸弹
We need to warn them. There may be other bombs out there.
并且彻查两起爆炸案中
And get all the information on any fragments
找到的全部碎片的信息
that were recovered from both bombings.
如果两颗炸弹有什么相同的部件
If those bombs were made with any common components,
或许能帮助拆弹小组解除贝克特踩的炸弹
it could help B.D.U. deactivate the device that Beckett's on.
没有解除密码  我们必须看看装置本身
Without the disarm code, We're gonna need to get eyes on the device.
我们用光纤探镜  从下面天花板往上看
We use a fiber-optic scope... Go in through the ceiling downstairs.
那样危险吗
Is that dangerous?
我们会尽可能降低危险
Well, we'll do everything we can to minimize the risk.
我们从屋子对面把线申过来
We'll start across the room, snake the cable over.
不过  还是会引起一定振动
Still, there'll be some vibrations.
-所以还是有可能  -做你该做的吧
- So there's always a chance that - Just do it.
我总不能一直站在这儿
I can't keep standing here forever.
好的  我们会尽快做完  但是也尽量小心
All right. We'll go as quick as we can but as slow as we have to.
谢谢
Thank you.
-卡塞尔  听我说  -我不走
- Castle, listen to me - I'm not leaving.
我知道  但是鉴于目前的情况
Look, I know, but depending on what happens,
我想要你帮我做件事
there's something that I need you to do--
我自己做不到的事
Something that I can't do myself.
要我帮你藏好黄片不让你爸爸发现吗
You need me to hide your porn stash so your dad doesn't find it?
你别闹了  好吗
Could you just be serious for a second, please?
好吧  说吧  要我做什么
Okay. What? What do you need me to do?
待会儿再说  但你得答应我你会做到
Not now, okay? Just promise me you'll do it.
好的  没问题
Yeah. Okay, yeah.
但是  你不用往这方面想的
But look, you don't need to be thinking like this.
我只是想实际一点  卡塞尔
I'm just--I'm trying to be realistic, Castle.
我都在这儿站了几小时了
I've been standing here for hours.
我开始觉得累了
And I'm feeling the fatigue set in.
别去想那个
Don't think about it.
击败疲劳只是
Beating fatigue is just, um...
用心智战胜身体
It's mind over body.
逃跑的战俘为获得自由能步行数百英里
Escaped P.O.W.s have walked hundreds of miles to gain their freedom.
极地探险家  欧内斯特·沙克尔顿
Polar explorer Ernest Shackleton
用救生艇划了八百英里  拯救了他的船员
rode in a lifeboat 800 miles to save his crew,
全都是靠
all because of...
你能说服自己相信一切
You can convince yourself of almost anything.
就像你让自己相信你没有迷恋我
Much like you convinced yourself you weren't crazy about me.
卡塞尔  我知道你这是干什么
Castle, I know what you're trying to do.
你想让我别去想这个
You're trying to take my mind off of it.
我也很感激  但我们真得要
And I appreciate that, but do we really have to--
对了  你或许能说服你自己  但是
And by the way, you may have convinced yourself, but...
你骗不了其他人
you weren't fooling anyone else--
骗不过我  更骗不过你的朋友们
Not me, and certainly not your friends.
是吗  因为从没有谁对我说过什么
Really? 'cause no one ever said anything to me.
还跟姐姐装蒜是吧
Girl, I'm gonna smack you.
你们每天形影不离地工作
You work side by side every day.
他以你为蓝本在书中大写性爱场景
He writes a sex scene in his book about you
看得我都要喝冰水降温
that had me reaching for ice water.
现在半路杀出来一个新娘旧情人
Now little Miss Bride shows up,
别告诉我你一点酸劲儿都没有
don't tell me you're not the least bit jealous.
得了吧  我看你在这里药水味闻太多了
Oh, please. You have been inhaling too many autopsy fluids.
亲爱的  不识庐山真面目
Honey, just because you can't see what's going on
只缘身在此山中
doesn't mean everyone else doesn't see what's going on.
闭嘴
Shut up.
他喜欢你
He's into you,
你明显也对他有好感  但是你决意
But you're determined not to give in to these feelings
不让那种感情影响你
that you clearly have for him.
于是他通过写作来抒发对你的幻想
So he fantasizes about you through his writing.
这简直就是书面意淫
It's literally...verbal masturbation.
不  我明白
No, no, no, no, no. I get it.
你为卡塞尔着迷
You're hot for Castle.
你想为他生小卡塞尔
You want to make little Castle babies.
不管你怎么掩饰  你迷恋着他
Despite your little act, you're crazy about him.
怎么  这难不成还是惊天大秘密啊
Oh, what? Was that supposed to be some big secret?
必须的
Yes.
好吧
No.
你觉得他知道吗
Do you think he knows?
把他完全交给你了
He's all yours.
好吧
Okay, okay.
她们或许说过什么
They might have said something, but--
但他们完全是搞错状况了
But they were completely misreading the situation.
就像你那么多次穿一些暴露的衣服
Oh. Much like I must have been misreading the situation
想要引起我瞩目
all those times you dressed up in revealing outfits
也是我自作多情了吗
to try and, uh, turn my head.
没有人...
"No one"...
隐藏身份  我喜欢
Undercover? I like it.
不过保险起见  最好再开一颗扣子
You might want to pop one more button, just in case.
这是我的幻觉  还是你真变了
Is it just my imagination, or did you change?
-卡塞尔  请叫支援好吗  -好的
- Castle, could you get some backup, please? - Yeah.
我变装都是为了卧底
The only reason that I was dressed up was to go undercover.
那么我每次都在场
Oh, I guess it was just a coincidence that...
就只是个巧合了
each time, I just so happened to be there.
不  那不是巧合
No, it wasn't a coincidence,
是因为你总是跟着我
because you were always following me around.
为什么呢  因为你喜欢我
Why? 'cause you were into me.
-我喜欢你  -对
- Me into you? - Yeah.
我承认  我并没有不被你吸引
Mm. I-I admit, I found you not unattractive
有时候
and occasionally...
也觉得你很风趣
fun to be around.
但是我才没有喜欢你呢
But into you? N-mm.
绝对没有
No. Definitely not.
那好吧  那你为什么跟着我
Okay, fine. Then why were you following me around?
别说是为了搜集素材
And don't say that it was research,
因为从来没人相信过这个理由
because no one believed that for a second.
你真想知道吗
You really want to know?
那是因为
It was because I was...
扮演警察真是太欢乐了
having so much fun playing cop.
发现尸体  太棒了
Dead body? Yes!
把枪放下  人渣
Drop the gun, dirtbag!
-你叫我什么  -人...人渣
- What did you call me? - D-dirt-dirtbag.
太好了
Boo-yah.
有没有在逃僵尸的警用代码
Is there a police code for zombie on the loose?
我爱死这个案子了
I love this case.
秘密  谋杀  赌博
Secrets, murder, and gambling--
我钟爱的娱乐活动之三
Three of my favorite pastimes.
抓住了
I got him!
中了  所以你承认
Bam! So you admit that it was you
-是你破坏了怀尔德的公寓  -卡塞尔
- who vandalized Wilder's apartment? - Castle.
有时忘了自己不是警察
I sometimes forget I'm not actually a cop.
要我再次上演《帅虎猛龙》的戏码吗
Want me to bust out Jake and the Fatman again?
我酝酿这个动作很久了耶
I've always wanted to do that!
放下你的枪  否则 我发誓我要-
Drop the gun or I swear to God, I'll--
看见了吗
Tell me you saw that!
抱歉了
Sorry!
帮个忙
Little help?
真不可思议
That was awesome.
我是说  显然这很可怕
I mean, well, obviously, it was horrible, but--
把手举起来
Put your hands in the air
最好给我跪在地上
and get on your knees while you're at it!
先生们  如果人生教了我什么道理
Gentlemen, if I've learned one thing,
那就是不要让凶案这种小事
it's to not let a little thing like murder
坏了我们玩乐的兴致
get in the way of having a good time.
你才不是因为这个一直跟着我
That's not why you were following me around.
这是其中之一
It is, too.
其他的事情
And anything else you come up with is...
都是你瞎想的
strictly a product of your imagination.
看来咱们两个是解决不了这件事了
Well, it's obvious that you and I are not gonna resolve this.
你承认先喜欢我了
So you concede?
有没有搞错
Seriously?
-谁先喜欢谁  -对
- Who like who first? - That's right.
谁先喜欢上谁的  我还是卡塞尔
Who was into whom first, me or Castle?
你知道我现在忙着救你的命吧
You do realize that I'm busy trying to save your life?
你回答就行了
Just answer the question,
埃斯波  别怕伤害你的朋友
Espo, and don't be afraid to hurt his feelings.
别忘了我们在我前女友婚礼上办案时
And don't forget about how jealous she got that time we worked that case
她有多嫉妒
at my ex-girlfriend's wedding.
也别忘了我和戴明在一起时他有多嫉妒
Or how jealous he got when I was with Demming.
在那之前  她看到我和我前妻在一起
Or before that, how jealous she got about me and my ex-wife.
你在和谁打电话
Who are you talking to?
那次你写的性爱场景
Or how about when you wrote that sex scene...
卡塞尔和贝克特
It's Castle and Beckett.
他们好像要撑不住了  听听
I think they're starting to crack. Check it out.
你嫉妒我和萨琳娜·凯耶
Or, uh, jealous about me and Serena Kaye,
还有中情局的索菲亚
or Sophia from the CIA,
和联调局的特工肖
or Agent Shaw from the FBI.
的确是撑不住了
Yeah, wow. Totally losing it.
我查了弗希以前袭击用的炸弹残片
Listen, I ran down the bomb fragments from Fosse's previous attacks.
他以前用的部件和现在完全不同
The components he used were completely different.
对现在这个炸弹的分析
They're not gonna be any help in determining
一点用都没有
what this third bomb is like.
现在就看拆弹小组了
So it's up to B.D.U. now.
我的天
Oh, God.
还有定时器
There's a timer, too.
应该是她踩上触发装置时
Seems like the timer was activated
定时器就开始倒数了
when she stepped on that triggering plate.
还剩多长时间
Okay. Well, how much time is left?
30分钟47秒
30 minutes and 47 seconds.
好吧
All right. Um...
我们能让它停止吗
Can we deactivate it by then?
我们会尽力的
We'll try.
问题是  我们通常处理的东西
Trouble is, our usual targets--
雷管  引爆装置和定时销
the fuse, the detonator, the timing pin--
都在钢板底下
they're all shielded by a steel plate.
总有办法的吧
Well, there's gotta be something we can do.
我们可以给地板铺上装甲
We could line the floor with armor.
我可以穿上拆弹小组的衣服
I could just put on one of those "Hurt Locker" suits.
然后把她撞飞下来
I could tackle her right off of it.
卡塞尔  如果那玩意爆炸了
Castle, if that thing goes off,
整栋大楼都保不住
the whole building's going with it.
这世上没有那种衣服
There's not a suit in the world that's gonna--
卡塞尔  怎么了
Hey, Castle. What's going on?
我马上过去
Uh, be right there.
我保证我会竭尽全力的
I promise we'll do all that we can.
但我劝你要有心理准备
But I urge you to be realistic--
谢谢你  警监  谢谢你
Okay, thank you. Captain, thank you.
他说了什么
What did he say?
好消息  他们把炸弹隔离了
Good news. They've isolated the bomb.
正在部署拆弹机器人工作
And they're deploying their bomb disposal robot.
那是一种先进的人工智能原型机
It's a new prototype model with advanced A.I.
模拟实战的时候都成功了
They've had a lot of success in field simulations. It's...
怎么了
What?
机器人原型机
A prototype robot?
我可以看得出你说谎  卡塞尔
I can tell when you're lying, Castle.
你知道的
You know that.
就像你说
Like when you said that you were...
你跟着我是为了扮演警察
following me just to play cop.
他到底说了什么
Now what did he actually say?
炸弹上有定时器
There's a timer on the bomb.
还有多久
How long?
大概三十分钟
About 30 minutes.
也无所谓了
Yeah, well, it's probably just as well.
我也快站不住了
I can't keep standing here anyway.
咱们会没事的
Hey, we will get you out of this.
你怎么这么确定
And what makes you so sure?
再糟糕的事我们也遇过啊
We've been in bad situations before.
现在听我的
Now here's what's gonna happen.
我们一起慢慢走到电梯那里
We're just gonna stroll on over to the elevator, together.
你出声  我就对着他的肝来一下
You make a sound, and I'll put a round in this man's liver,
他会慢慢死去
and he will die slowly.
你到底想离死亡有多近呢
How close to death do you want to get?
卡塞尔
Castle!
看到了吗
Are you watching?
你的女人在我手上
I got your girl!
我觉得  这种情况下
I feel, in situations like this,
有信念很重要
it's important to have faith.
救命
Help!
卡塞尔
Castle!
Castle,
谢谢你
thank you...
陪着我
for being there.
我一直都在
Always.
是的  我们似乎
Yeah, there is something about us
有卷入麻烦的体质
that seems to draw in trouble.
但你忘了最惊魂的那次
But you're forgetting the scariest one of them all.
理查德  我回来了
Richard, I'm home!
我的天
Oh, my god. Aah!
儿子  我们得谈谈
Darling, we need to talk.
躲起来
Hide.
-什么  -躲起来
What? Hide.
-你说真的吗  -躲到衣橱里
- Are you serious? - Get in the closet.
不  我才不躲到衣橱里呢
No, I'm not going in the closet.
快躲到衣橱里
Get in the closet.
出什么事了
What's going on?
我只是...
I'm just...
在铺床
making the bed.
真是吓死人了
That was terrifying.
但是  尽管
But still,
局面糟糕透顶  我们总会解决办法
as bad as the situation gets, we always find a way out.
好吧
Okay, fine.
那这次又该怎么解决呢
So how are we gonna find our way out of this one?
我觉得答案就在弗希的故事里
I keep thinking the answer is in Fosse's story.
他肯定是因为什么事气疯了  但是什么事呢
I mean, something must have set him off. But what?
卡塞尔  他的故事有什么重要的呢
Castle, why does his story matter?
故事总是至关重要的
The story always matters.
这就是我们合拍的原因
That's actually why we make such a great team.
你追查证据
You find the evidence,
证据助我构架故事
evidence helps me build a story,
故事指引我们找到答案
the story points us to the solution.
房卡
The key card.
迈克的房卡
Mike's key card!
是斯嘉丽给他的
Scarlett gave it to him
这样他们才能一起打理生意
so that the two of them could go into business together.
这让勒索者很生气
Making for one angry blackmailer.
他对达尔来说就是个威胁
And as long as he's alive, he's a threat to Dahl.
从一开始  她就在计划这一切
She was in on it from the start.
是的  你怎么知道
Yes. How did you know?
心有灵犀
I was thinking the exact same thing.
我知道扎尔曼要杀害的目标了
I think I figured out who Zalman was paid to kill.
亿万富翁慈善家克里斯琴·达尔
Billionaire philanthropist Christian Dahl?
咱俩就像一对双胞胎
It's like we could be twins.
我想我知道凶手是谁了
I think I know who the killer is.
他  什么
Him. What?
他撒谎了
He lied?
骗局还没结束
The con is still on!
这里
There!
我知道凶手是谁了
I know who the killer is!
我们不在的时候  你们练习接话吗
Do you two practice this when we're not around?
你看  故事
See? The story--
就是我们的秘密配方
It's our secret ingredient.
除了你的故事编得
Except when your storytelling devolves
过分离谱的时候
into wild speculation.
那些根本就是瞎胡闹
Then it's just maddening.
我的那些疯狂猜想
Hey, that wild speculation
几乎总能领我们找到凶手
almost always points us to our killer.
我实在搞不懂什么人会偷尸体
You know what I don't get, is who would steal a dead body?
非法器官贩卖者
Organ harvesters.
急缺尸体标本的医学院学生
Cadaverless med students.
撒旦的信徒
Satanists.
想制造怪物的科学狂人
Mad scientists looking to create their own monster.
那子弹是冰块做的
The bullet was made of ice.
持枪的维京人  这就是你的推测
Gun-toting viking, that's your theory?
或者是吸血鬼  是最近刚被解雇的邮局职工
Or he's a vampire. Recently fired postal workers.
我现在正寻找线索
Here I am, looking for evidence,
而你们却靠编故事了事
and all I had to do was just make something up.
这个钟是被一个秘密组织用来
The clock was commissioned by a secret society
倒数世界末日的
to countdown the end of days--
一个由圣诞老人组成的秘密组织
A secret society of santas,
他们守护着时间
who are the guardians of time.
这想法太拉风了
Oh-ho! Oh, that's good.
不要说间谍
Don't say spy.
也别说是黑帮干的
Or mob hit.
那黑帮干掉了一个间谍呢
Mob hit of a spy?
暗杀忍者
Ninja assassin.
疯子医生  低成本电影里的纳粹
Mad doctors and b-movie Nazis.
时空旅行杀手
Time-traveling killer.
也许...
Maybe...
没  没有想到
No, I got nothing.
木乃伊自己从棺木里爬出来
The mummy himself has risen from the grave
在纽约街头闲逛  寻找复仇的对象
and is roaming new york seeking vengeance.
如果真是鬼魂的话  就太酷了
Ooh. That'd be cool, if it was actually a ghost.
别拿逻辑来分析我的故事
Don't ruin my story with your logic.
碟片本身不会置你于死地  埃斯波西托
The actual DVD will not kill me, Esposito.
是里面的怨魂
It will be the spirit inside the DVD,
就像《午夜凶铃》里那样
just like in "The Ring."
这是你说过的最蠢的话了
Yeah, that's the stupidest thing you said yet.
半机械人杀手从未来被派到这里
So a killer cyborg sent from the future,
反抗军截取了他的坐标
resistance fighters intercept his coordinates,
将他传送进了披萨烤箱  拯救了人类
redirect him into a pizza oven, saving humanity.
要什么证据啊  这么精彩的故事
Who needs proof? What a great story.
黑衣人
Men In Black.
这个灵媒预言了自己的谋杀案
The psychic predicted her own murder?
凶手是个僵尸
The killer's a zombie.
我说了是"几乎总能"
I said "almost always."
但这次事件里  我们并没在追捕凶手
But in this case, we're not trying to catch our killer.
凶手已经死了
Fosse's already dead.
你知道  我最不解的是什么吗
You know what bugs me?
一个到处安炸弹的人
Why would a guy on a bombing spree
会关心出售棒球卡片这样的事吗
be worried about selling his baseball card collection?
他不会
He wouldn't.
你认为弗希
Do you think that Fosse
是想引诱收藏家来这里吗
was trying to lure the collector here?
我是这么想的  他的收据说明
Yeah, I'd say so, seeing as how this receipt says
几周前他刚刚买了一套卡片
he just bought this collection a week ago.
那个收藏家要到局里来
That card collector was going down to the station
录口供  对吗
to make a statement, right?
如果他还在那  也许莱恩跟埃斯波西托
Yes, yes. If he's still there, maybe Ryan and Esposito
-能查出弗希找他的真正原因  -这就联系他们
- can figure out what Fosse wanted with him. - Already on it.
你确定以前没见过他
You're sure you never met him before?
-一点交集都没有  -没有
- No previous interactions? - No.
几周前他在脸书上加我好友
He friended me on Facebook a few weeks ago,
看到我交换卡片的帖子
saw me posting about some trading cards,
说他有一些旧的卡让我看看
said he has some old ones for me to take a look at.
那和他的审讯有联系吗  间接的也算
How about any connection to his trial, even indirectly?
没准的你的工作多少和法律是相关的
Maybe your job's related to the legal field somehow.
我在奥尔巴尼的纽约州教育部担任管理员
I'm an administrator for N.Y.S.E.D. up in Albany.
这是我这么多年
This is the first time
第一次来市里
I've even been to the city in years.
那他的被害人呢  杰弗里·斯科拉和凯利·兰瑟
Okay, what about his victims, Jeffrey Sklar, Kelly Runther?
和他们有联系吗
Any connection to them?
对不起  我从没见过他们
Sorry. I've never seen them before.
那这些和弗希审判相关的人呢
What about this list of names connected to the fosse trial?
有熟悉的名字吗
Do any of those names look familiar?
再看一遍  我们快没时间了
Look again. We're running out of time.
我也想帮忙  但是我什么都不知道
I want to help. I do. But I don't know anything.
是  不  我明白  谢谢埃斯波西托
Yeah. No, I under--I understand. Thank you, Esposito.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
还有十分钟  我懂
Ten minutes. I know.
没事的  警监  你尽力了
It's okay, Captain. You did everything you could.
我们不会放弃的
We are not giving up.
下面的兄弟们还会努力
There'll be guys down there working on this
到最后一刻的
till the last possible moment.
但是我得让这里的人撤退
But I have to withdraw everybody else,
-也包括你  卡塞尔  -我能
- and that includes you, Castle. - Could I just...
我能和他单独说几句话吗
Could I have a moment alone with him, please?
当然
Of course.
到说再见的时候了
It's time to say good-bye.
我不走
I'm not leaving.
卡塞尔  你答应过我时机到了
Castle, you promised that you would help me with something
就会帮我的
when the time came.
现在时机到了
This is it.
-贝克特  不  -求你了  卡塞尔
- Beckett, no. - Please, Castle.
求你别让这件事难上加难了
Please don't make this any harder than it needs to be.
我希望我可以
I wish I could...
吻你
kiss you.
我还有好多
I wish...
和你有关的愿望
so many things.
不
No.
我们没有遗憾
There's no regrets.
这一路走来  一切很美好
All in all, I think we've had a great run.
你该走了
You should go.
里奇
Rick.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
您已拨通了吉姆·贝克特的语音信箱
You've reached the voice mail of Jim Beckett.
请留言
Please leave a message.
嘿  爸爸  是我
Hey, dad, it's me.
我只想听听你的声音
I just wanted to hear your voice and...
我想告诉你我爱你
I wanted to tell you that I love you.
好了  就这样
Okay, that's all.
拜
Bye.
我们为死者伸冤
We speak for the dead.
这是工作
That's the job.
一旦坏人夺去了他们的声音
We are all they've got
我们就是他们的全部
once the wicked rob them of their voices.
这是我们欠他们的
We owe them that.
但我们不欠他们我们自己的生活
But we don't owe 'em our lives.
你妈妈经常说  生活中
Your mother always said that life
没有我们面对不了的事
never delivers anything that we can't handle.
让我带你走吧  凯特
Let me take you someplace, Kate.
去个你会安全的地方
Someplace you'll be safe.
我再无宁日了
I'll never be safe.
没有胜利
There are no victories.
只有战斗
There's only the battle.
你所能期望的最好的事情
And the best that you could hope for
就是你能够找到自己的立场
Is that you find someplace where you can make your stand.
我希望找到一个
I wish that I had someone
可以守候我的人  我可以守候他
Who would be there for me, and I could be there for him,
两人可以长相厮守
And we could just dive into it together.
即便是在最糟糕的日子里
Even on the worst days,
也有快乐的可能
there's a possibility for joy.
凯特
Kate!
在频临死亡的那一刻
I almost died,
我心里想的只有你
and all I could think about was you.
我只想跟你在一起
I just want you.
别死在我面前
Don't die on me!
加油
Come on!
交换  我们来吧
Switch. We got this.
脉搏  我们不能等了  准备插管
Pulse ox... we can't wait. Set up for intubation.
凯特
Kate.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你  凯特
I love you, Kate.
嘿  你干嘛呢
Hey. What are you doing?
小睡吗  我可以一会儿再过来
Napping? 'cause I can come back later.
卡塞尔  你在这儿干嘛
Castle, what are you doing here?
你答应我了
You promised.
是  我是答应你离开
Yeah, I promised I'd leave,
但是我没答应我不会回来
but I didn't promise I wouldn't come back.
我买咖啡了  一会儿吧  庆祝你脱险
I got coffee--later-- for when you're off that thing.
不  卡塞尔  你马上走吧
No, Castle, please. You have to leave now.
没必要我们两个人一起死
There's no reason for both of us to die.
我不是来这儿死的  我来这里拆弹的
Oh, I didn't come here to die. I came here to defuse the bomb.
还有机会
There's still a chance.
-是 十万分之一的机会  -好极了
- Yes, a 1 in 100,000 chance. - Great.
既然还有机会  我就不会放弃
While there's still a chance, I'm not giving up.
卡塞尔  听我说
Castle, listen to me.
我已经平静接受了
I've already come to peace with this,
但我不能接受阿丽克西斯失去她的父亲
and that doesn't include Alexis losing her father
或者玛莎失去她的儿子
or Martha her son.
别这样  我能怎样做  你一个人
Come on. What am I supposed to do, walk out the door
孤孤单单站在这里  而我一走了之
while you're standing all the way over there by yourself?
是  这正是
Yes. Yes, that's exactly--
等一下
Wait a second.
你站的地方是屋子的内部
Why are you standing all the way over there?
如果弗希是给警察设计的炸弹  为什么
If Fosse set the bomb for the cops, why not--
为什么不埋在门口好让他们一进来就踩到呢
Why not set it by the door so they'd hit is as they came in?
除非  这不是给警察的
Unless-- this wasn't for cops.
那是给谁设计的
Then who was it for?
那个收藏卡片的小子  他叫什么
The card collector kid-- what was his name?
迪亚哥  他当时要来这里
Diego. He was on his way up here.
或许弗希打算要挟他以获得信息
Maybe Fosse was trying to leverage him for information.
好  太棒了
Okay, great.
所以说  你站的地方离哪里最近
So, uh, what's near where you're standing?
厨台  卡片
The Island, cards,
笔记本电脑
computer.
卡塞尔  我觉得我可以够到电脑
Castle, I think I can reach that computer from here.
你待在那  我来看看
You stay there. I'll check it.
你觉得弗希想让迪亚哥查什么东西吗
Do you think Fosse wanted Diego to look something up?
也许  但会是什么呢
Maybe, but what?
正在看浏览历史  A片
Checking the browser history--porn...
还是A片
more porn,
几个私家侦探的网站
web sites for a couple of PIs
职业人肉网
PeopleTracker.Pro.
他在找人
He's looking for someone.
或许把他送进监狱的
Maybe it was someone else
另有其人
that he held responsible for putting him in prison.
鼠标一点就能找到人
You can find practically anyone with the click of a mouse.
为什么请私家侦探
Why hire a private investigator?
我有答案
I think I might have an answer for you.
我查阅了与弗希一案有关的
I went through the list of all the people
人员名单
involved in Fosse's trial.
有一个女人的资料被系统抹去了
One woman's been completely scrubbed from the system.
驾照信息
Driver's license,
社保信息  都不见了
social security number-- all gone.
那人是谁
Who was that?
桃乐西·诺瓦克
Dorothy Novak.
控方的重要证人
The prosecution's main witness,
弗希当时的女友
and Fosse's girlfriend at the time.
地检官刚刚确认  检察院在弗希出狱后
The D.A. just confirmed, his office set her up
给她提供了新的身份
with a new identity when fosse got out three months ago.
她害怕弗希会报复
She was afraid Fosse would come after her.
看起来她是对的
Looks like she was right.
迪亚哥·胡梅纳兹如何帮助他
Okay, but how is this Diego Jiminez
-找到她呢  -不知道
- supposed to help find her? - Don't know.
他在NYSED工作
He worked at the N.Y.S.E.D.
纽约州教育部
New York State Education Department.
等下
Wait.
头两个被害人与弗希女友有联系吗
Were the first two victims related to Fosse's girlfriend?
有  昨天被杀的女人是弗希女友的表亲
Yeah, the woman he killed last night was the girlfriend's cousin.
第一个被害人在检察院工作
And the first victim worked for the D.A.'s office.
-他们帮忙转移了她  -弗希不想复仇
- They helped relocate her. - Fosse didn't want revenge.
他想从他们那得到想要的讯息
He was looking for information from them.
他想知道女友的新身份
He wanted to find out his girlfriend's new identity.
他迫切地想要找出线索
He was desperate to find them.
卡塞尔
Castle.
我知道  她有孩子吗
Right there with you. Does she have a kid?
是的  她在审讯后八个月分娩
Yeah. She gave birth eight months after the trial.
你怎么知道
How did you know?
是弗希的  他出狱后才知道
It's his. He didn't find out about it until he got out.
所以他把迪亚哥引到这里
And that's why he lured Diego here.
迪亚哥能够查阅州内学校的学生资料
Diego had access to state school records.
他想找到他的孩子  一切都是为了找到
He was trying to find his kid. It was all about fi--
那就是密码
That's the code.
一定是
It has to be.
莱恩  看看你能不能找到孩子的名字
Ryan, see if you can find the kid's name.
正在找
Working on it.
快点  兄弟  我们还有两分钟
Okay, work fast, buddy. We got two minutes.
这个理论合情合理
It's a story that makes sense.
弗希想在死前见见自己的骨肉
Fosse was desperate to see his kid just once before he dies,
但是母亲把孩子藏起来了
but the mother has hidden the child away.
于是弗希抓狂了
So Fosse lashed out,
不惜一切想要找到他们
doing whatever it took to track them down.
我就说我们解决这事
Told you we'd figure this out.
卡塞尔  还有一分钟多钟
Castle, there's barely a minute left.
-你得离开这  -还不行
- You've gotta go. - Not yet.
求你了  如果他找到名字  我自己输入
Please. If he finds the name, I'll type it in myself.
-如果没找  -他会找到的
- If not-- - He'll come through.
一定会
He has to.
威廉
William.
孩子的名字叫威廉
The kid's name is William.
七个字母
Seven letters.
比利
Billy.
或威力
Or Willy.
哪个白痴妈妈会给孩子起名叫威力
What kind of mother is gonna call her kid willy
除非她希望自己的孩子在学校天天被欺负
unless she wants his ass kicked every day at the playground?
伙计们  15秒
Guys, 15 seconds.
你来决定  贝克特
Your call, Beckett.
比利  快
Billy. Go.
B-I-L-L
B-I-L-L...
老天
Oh, god.
她走下来了
She's off.
她安全了  太好了
She's off. Yes.
等下  卡塞尔  听着
Wait, Castle. Listen...
谢谢你陪着我
Thank you for staying with me.
我一直都在
Always.
时间把握地刚好
Perfect timing.
还好吗
You good?
-还好  她看见了吗  -没有
- Yeah. Did she see? - No.
很高兴见到你  探长  甚至高兴见到你  卡塞尔
Glad to see you, Detective. Even you, Mr. Castle.
我得说
I have to say,
据我所知  没有多少人会像你那样做
I don't know too many men who would've done what you did.
是啊
Neither do I.
拜托  探长
Oh, for heaven's sake, Detective.
赶紧亲一口吧
Just kiss the man.
长官  你知道
Sir, you know?
怎么
What...
你以为我是白痴吗
Do you think I'm an idiot?
我需要保持可信的推诿
I needed to maintain plausible deniability,
只要你们
which I can continue
在分局能够专注工作  我会继续下去
as long as you two both act professionally at the precinct.
我是可以
I know I can.
但是  警监  她经常在工作时
But, Captain, she has a long history
对我动手动脚
of coming on to me at work--
放心  长官  那不会构成任何问题
I don't think it'll be a problem, sir.
很好
Good.
与此同时  既然我们达成共识
Meanwhile, as long as we're on neutral ground here,
我得说  他值得
I'd say, uh, he's deserves it.
不是吗
Wouldn't you?
是的  长官
Yes, sir, I would.
卡塞尔  我站在那
You know, Castle, when I was standing up there,
一直在想我们无数次的亲吻
I kept thinking about all the times we've kissed.
我在选择最棒的一次
And I was trying to decide on the best one.
然后呢
And what do you think?
我觉得我们才刚刚开始
I think we're just getting started.